<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: A Brief Psychohistory of Indian Politics-Delhi Elections	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 19:49:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Arvind Subu		</title>
		<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/comment-page-1/#comment-19</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arvind Subu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 20:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections#comment-19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Accept he had &#039;hashtag&#039; support on twitter.. Even a Congress spokesperson Mr.Americai Narayanan has been a twitter sensation for weeks .. Twitter is a like a mirage.. you can see something from a long distance.. it never exists in reality :-p .. I believe all the AAP hoopla last time was the creation of the IBN network.. The media house helped the AAP movement to get a national flavour, which is difficult now.. I do accept it doesnt have much of an effect in Delhi as its a small state.. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last time around Modi had not become the PM if I am right.. Moreover , i dont think he campaigned in Delhi more than a couple of occasions... So,, this time around all the dynamics change.. Personally feel the so called secular anti BJP votes will not convert into seats for the AAP .. And finally.. as I mentioned earlier, we already have more than enough regional parties to split the opposition votes..no need of a pseudo Congress party.. .. Lets wait and watch what happens :-) .. Cheers ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Accept he had &#39;hashtag&#39; support on twitter.. Even a Congress spokesperson Mr.Americai Narayanan has been a twitter sensation for weeks .. Twitter is a like a mirage.. you can see something from a long distance.. it never exists in reality :-p .. I believe all the AAP hoopla last time was the creation of the IBN network.. The media house helped the AAP movement to get a national flavour, which is difficult now.. I do accept it doesnt have much of an effect in Delhi as its a small state.. </p>
<p>Last time around Modi had not become the PM if I am right.. Moreover , i dont think he campaigned in Delhi more than a couple of occasions&#8230; So,, this time around all the dynamics change.. Personally feel the so called secular anti BJP votes will not convert into seats for the AAP .. And finally.. as I mentioned earlier, we already have more than enough regional parties to split the opposition votes..no need of a pseudo Congress party.. .. Lets wait and watch what happens 🙂 .. Cheers </p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Easwar		</title>
		<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/comment-page-1/#comment-18</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Easwar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections#comment-18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I predict a close contest, where BJP has an edge. And complete rout of Congress.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I predict a close contest, where BJP has an edge. And complete rout of Congress.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Easwar		</title>
		<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/comment-page-1/#comment-17</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Easwar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 18:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections#comment-17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nice to see some contradicting opinions.&lt;br /&gt;I ll nevertheless try to defend my analysis.&lt;br /&gt;Your first argument was that, there was no one who actually liked the AAP government. &lt;br /&gt;I didn&#039;t say that the 49 day rule was full of reforms, I just said that some people( i.e the AAP bhakths) saw them full of reforms. From hasthags on twitter we can see that still there are a lot of hardcore AAP and Kejriwal supporters. We can&#039;t deny that fact. Though I personally feel that the 49 day rule was a nothing but full of impractical ideas and drama.&lt;br /&gt;Then your next argument was that I didn&#039;t take into account the NaMo factor.&lt;br /&gt;The NaMo factor existed in the previous elections too. The BJP bakths will punch the same button again. And I did mention that the middle class vote will be split and it will go to the BJP because of that 49 day drama.&lt;br /&gt;Even if IBN doesn&#039;t do the coverage, someone else will and Delhi is a city state, so door to door campaigning would suffice.&lt;br /&gt;And one point you don&#039;t see is that there is a good number of anti BJP groups. They will certainly cast their votes for AAP. This is a big plus for them, even though they might lose on the neutral middle class votes.&lt;br /&gt;Then for the last part of Congress Mukth Bharath, If AAP does come to power, we don&#039;t grow another Congress which completely overshadows Congress( except maybe in Delhi) but a party that can split the votes of Congress. This will certainly help BJP.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nice to see some contradicting opinions.<br />I ll nevertheless try to defend my analysis.<br />Your first argument was that, there was no one who actually liked the AAP government. <br />I didn&#39;t say that the 49 day rule was full of reforms, I just said that some people( i.e the AAP bhakths) saw them full of reforms. From hasthags on twitter we can see that still there are a lot of hardcore AAP and Kejriwal supporters. We can&#39;t deny that fact. Though I personally feel that the 49 day rule was a nothing but full of impractical ideas and drama.<br />Then your next argument was that I didn&#39;t take into account the NaMo factor.<br />The NaMo factor existed in the previous elections too. The BJP bakths will punch the same button again. And I did mention that the middle class vote will be split and it will go to the BJP because of that 49 day drama.<br />Even if IBN doesn&#39;t do the coverage, someone else will and Delhi is a city state, so door to door campaigning would suffice.<br />And one point you don&#39;t see is that there is a good number of anti BJP groups. They will certainly cast their votes for AAP. This is a big plus for them, even though they might lose on the neutral middle class votes.<br />Then for the last part of Congress Mukth Bharath, If AAP does come to power, we don&#39;t grow another Congress which completely overshadows Congress( except maybe in Delhi) but a party that can split the votes of Congress. This will certainly help BJP.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Arvind Subu		</title>
		<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/comment-page-1/#comment-16</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arvind Subu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 17:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections#comment-16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nice to read about your views on the political situation in our national capital..I respect your sentiments but I completely have a contradicting position on the case. My ideas are due to my infinitesimal understanding of the scenario , so excuse me if there are any glaring mistakes. :-) ... The first thing that struck me hard in your post is the portion which said &#039;some people saw a government full of reforms&#039; !! .. The whole 40 odd day debacle by AAP was a circus and not a government ,,, I never read the views of &#039;these people&#039; in any national tabloids ,, praying my memory is right.. Second , you have talked about the change in scenario between the last elections and the coming one. The key point to note here is the presence of  Narendra Modi. Here is a leader , who has singlehandedly shown the door to seasoned veterans like the Pawars and Thackreys during the past few months. &#039;Khujliwals&#039; wont be much of a contest for him. Modi is not a hardline right winger to alienate the center and left , this too works in his favor. Personally, I too felt that Kejriwal was a good activist, but he never was a leader from day one.. The party&#039;s credibility too took a hit after the exit of prominent members like Kiran Bedi and V.K.Singh to name a few. Another change since last time is his loss of &#039;support&#039; from the IBN media house which had gone out of the way to cover his antics last year..&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, I donot understand your logic for a Congress Mukth Bharath , you are suggesting BJP to let AAP grow and take its place!! Isn&#039;t it better to have the anti BJP votes going to smaller regional parties rather than some leaderless movement lacking credibility..&lt;br /&gt;Bottom line.. I feel its gonna be a sweep for the Bharthiya Janata Party (50+) and AAP dwindling in single digits (winning only in the Sikh/Muslim dominated areas)... Rather than Delhi, its gonna be Kashmir which is to be an interesting fight for the BJP ,, .. Jai Hind :-)&lt;br /&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nice to read about your views on the political situation in our national capital..I respect your sentiments but I completely have a contradicting position on the case. My ideas are due to my infinitesimal understanding of the scenario , so excuse me if there are any glaring mistakes. 🙂 &#8230; The first thing that struck me hard in your post is the portion which said &#39;some people saw a government full of reforms&#39; !! .. The whole 40 odd day debacle by AAP was a circus and not a government ,,, I never read the views of &#39;these people&#39; in any national tabloids ,, praying my memory is right.. Second , you have talked about the change in scenario between the last elections and the coming one. The key point to note here is the presence of  Narendra Modi. Here is a leader , who has singlehandedly shown the door to seasoned veterans like the Pawars and Thackreys during the past few months. &#39;Khujliwals&#39; wont be much of a contest for him. Modi is not a hardline right winger to alienate the center and left , this too works in his favor. Personally, I too felt that Kejriwal was a good activist, but he never was a leader from day one.. The party&#39;s credibility too took a hit after the exit of prominent members like Kiran Bedi and V.K.Singh to name a few. Another change since last time is his loss of &#39;support&#39; from the IBN media house which had gone out of the way to cover his antics last year..</p>
<p>Also, I donot understand your logic for a Congress Mukth Bharath , you are suggesting BJP to let AAP grow and take its place!! Isn&#39;t it better to have the anti BJP votes going to smaller regional parties rather than some leaderless movement lacking credibility..<br />Bottom line.. I feel its gonna be a sweep for the Bharthiya Janata Party (50+) and AAP dwindling in single digits (winning only in the Sikh/Muslim dominated areas)&#8230; Rather than Delhi, its gonna be Kashmir which is to be an interesting fight for the BJP ,, .. Jai Hind 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Arvind Subu		</title>
		<link>/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections/comment-page-1/#comment-15</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arvind Subu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 16:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/11/08/a-brief-psychohistory-of-indian-politics-delhi-elections#comment-15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This comment has been removed by the author.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This comment has been removed by the author.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>