<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Can atheism be a path to attain god?	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 20:01:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Easwar		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-9</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Easwar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 17:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And I liked your theory about life. :)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And I liked your theory about life. 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Easwar		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-8</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Easwar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 17:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-8</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Einstein was a clerk before he published his three famous papers. So science is not limited to physicists or mathematicians.Anyone can be a pursuer.&lt;br /&gt;And as you said there is no necessity for finding the unifying theory. &lt;br /&gt;The same goes for the theory of gravity. The theory is not a necessity. Whether you understand it or not, it exists.&lt;br /&gt;And by end of the tunnel, I meant the ultimate goal in your life, or meaning/purpose in your life.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Einstein was a clerk before he published his three famous papers. So science is not limited to physicists or mathematicians.Anyone can be a pursuer.<br />And as you said there is no necessity for finding the unifying theory. <br />The same goes for the theory of gravity. The theory is not a necessity. Whether you understand it or not, it exists.<br />And by end of the tunnel, I meant the ultimate goal in your life, or meaning/purpose in your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Kesavan		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-7</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kesavan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 15:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-7</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don&#039;t understand why someone must have a path at all...I don&#039;t think it&#039;s the atheist&#039;s &#039;path&#039; to find the truth by finding the unifying theory. It&#039;s probably a physicists&#039; or of a mathematician&#039;s long time goal. I don&#039;t think there is a necessity for a unifying theory to explain most things in this universe. For instance, if you have enough intelligence about what&#039;s going on around you, you can predict to an extent of what is going to happen next. I guess the weather predicting system is a primitive form of this idea.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By end of the tunnel, do you mean destiny? If yes, then I reject the notion of that as well. We are here because of some cosmic accident and not because we were always destined to be here and I don&#039;t think everyone has a purpose in life and must choose a path to fulfill it. To put it bluntly it&#039;s more like, life just exists and it can cease to exist at any time. We are just part of an elaborate ecosystem, and our place on earth is as important/unimportant as that of a bacteria.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#39;t understand why someone must have a path at all&#8230;I don&#39;t think it&#39;s the atheist&#39;s &#39;path&#39; to find the truth by finding the unifying theory. It&#39;s probably a physicists&#39; or of a mathematician&#39;s long time goal. I don&#39;t think there is a necessity for a unifying theory to explain most things in this universe. For instance, if you have enough intelligence about what&#39;s going on around you, you can predict to an extent of what is going to happen next. I guess the weather predicting system is a primitive form of this idea.</p>
<p>By end of the tunnel, do you mean destiny? If yes, then I reject the notion of that as well. We are here because of some cosmic accident and not because we were always destined to be here and I don&#39;t think everyone has a purpose in life and must choose a path to fulfill it. To put it bluntly it&#39;s more like, life just exists and it can cease to exist at any time. We are just part of an elaborate ecosystem, and our place on earth is as important/unimportant as that of a bacteria.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Easwar		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-5</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Easwar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 06:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I never generalized that Atheists blindly disbelieve god.&lt;br /&gt;Belief or disbelief in something is not the end of the tunnel. &lt;br /&gt;I think both a theist and atheist after choosing their paths must try to find the truth.&lt;br /&gt;You might ask me what is this truth that I always talk about. I think in the case of atheists you must find that unifying theory that explains everything in this universe. &lt;br /&gt;I hope you have read &quot;A brief history of Time&quot; by Stephen Hawking, he discusses about the future of science, and says that the ultimate goal will be to find this unifying theory.&lt;br /&gt;Your responsibility as an atheist doesn&#039;t end at you just disbelieving in god.&lt;br /&gt;This is something that I think personally, everyone must pursue the truth in his own path.&lt;br /&gt;Atheism is just a path.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I never generalized that Atheists blindly disbelieve god.<br />Belief or disbelief in something is not the end of the tunnel. <br />I think both a theist and atheist after choosing their paths must try to find the truth.<br />You might ask me what is this truth that I always talk about. I think in the case of atheists you must find that unifying theory that explains everything in this universe. <br />I hope you have read &#8220;A brief history of Time&#8221; by Stephen Hawking, he discusses about the future of science, and says that the ultimate goal will be to find this unifying theory.<br />Your responsibility as an atheist doesn&#39;t end at you just disbelieving in god.<br />This is something that I think personally, everyone must pursue the truth in his own path.<br />Atheism is just a path.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Kesavan		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-2</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kesavan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 05:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-2</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I would like to add a few points about atheism since I feel that the concept has been slightly misunderstood here. Atheists do not blindly disbelieve in god. We do not believe in any supernatural entity who is commonly known as the creator or the driving force of everything, because there is no evidence that suggests that such a thing exists. And the concept of god itself is introduced not by an atheist but by a religious person. So the burden of proof rests with the believer who has to provide the evidence for god and their existence since they invented that concept. I can say my hand is made of gold, and I believe that wholeheartedly. And I can call you a disbeliever of this &#039;fact&#039; that my hand is made of gold. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I would like to add a few points about atheism since I feel that the concept has been slightly misunderstood here. Atheists do not blindly disbelieve in god. We do not believe in any supernatural entity who is commonly known as the creator or the driving force of everything, because there is no evidence that suggests that such a thing exists. And the concept of god itself is introduced not by an atheist but by a religious person. So the burden of proof rests with the believer who has to provide the evidence for god and their existence since they invented that concept. I can say my hand is made of gold, and I believe that wholeheartedly. And I can call you a disbeliever of this &#39;fact&#39; that my hand is made of gold. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Kesavan		</title>
		<link>/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god/comment-page-1/#comment-1</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kesavan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 05:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/16/can-atheism-be-a-path-to-attain-god#comment-1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This comment has been removed by the author.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This comment has been removed by the author.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>