<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>easwaraiyer &#8211; easwar.eth</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/easwaraiyer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 02:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://s0.wp.com/i/webclip.png</url>
	<title>easwaraiyer &#8211; easwar.eth</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">80070271</site>	<item>
		<title>Crypto Mama</title>
		<link>/2021/06/03/crypto-mama/</link>
					<comments>/2021/06/03/crypto-mama/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 01:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/06/03/crypto-mama/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Easwara!, what is your opinion on this bitcoin thing. Have you done any investment in it?”, asked Pattabhi mama. “No mama, I am not in for any speculation. And I think I have also inherited the family trait of taking no risk and remaining poor. Hence I have remained aloof from it. But the crypto&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/06/03/crypto-mama/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Easwara!, what is your opinion on this bitcoin thing. Have you done any investment in it?”, asked Pattabhi mama.</p>
<p>“No mama, I am not in for any speculation. And I think I have also inherited the family trait of taking no risk and remaining poor. Hence I have remained aloof from it. But the crypto technology looks promising, I’ll adopt it whenever it becomes mainstream.”, I said.</p>
<p>“What promising technology?”, asked Pattabhi mama.</p>
<p>“One use case is smart contracts mama. You bought that land alongside that highway project 10 years ago saying that the value will double in 2 years right?”</p>
<p>“Yes da, Highway also didn’t come, Buyer also didn’t come.”</p>
<p>“Yes mama, even back then I did admire your confidence on an investment based on a highway project in Kerala. Recently only one highway project was completed with much fanfare, the foundation stone for the project was laid during the Chera dynasty.</p>
<p>Okay, coming back to smart contracts, say you do have a buyer and he says he’ll come up with the money in 3 months time and wants you to hold the sale. You ask him to pay some deposit. If he doesn’t come up with the money in 3 months you don’t have to return the deposit.</p>
<p>Say you also have an agreement that if he returns to you with a “no” in 7 days, you pay back the deposit. You can make a smart contract for that, it automatically takes care if the conditions are met and does the money transfer.”</p>
<p>“Oho!” exclaimed Pattabhi mama.</p>
<p>“You can do that using the Ethereum network, they are based on the principle that ‘Code is law’.”, I said.</p>
<p>“Ayyayyo”</p>
<p>What “Ayyayyo” mama?</p>
<p>“Dei Easwara, Indian government passes law through Lok Sabha, Rajya Sabha and the President. Even then our laws are apdi ipdi only. If fellows like you write code and say code is law na, damal dumeel only. The whole world will descend into chaos.”</p>
<p>I don’t know what made him gain that impression of me, probably the time I said I ll make his smart phone faster and ended up erasing all his contacts. Since then Pattabhi mama keeps only theoretical discussions on technology with me. When it comes to execution he goes to Kamala Mobiles near Shakthan Stand.</p>
<p>“Valid point mama, probably technology will develop to a point that even coding becomes idiot proof.”, I said.</p>
<p>“Yes yes, very very necessary.”, said Pattabhi mama rubbing Dettol in the already inflicted wound.</p>
<p>“Why this sudden interest in bitcoin?” I asked.</p>
<p>“All this pandemic situation looks very gloomy, so I thought I should diversify my portfolio.”, said Pattabhi Mama.</p>
<p>“Oho. How much pension are you receiving?”, I asked. Pattabhi mama is quite free in discussing financial matters since he is confident that I wouldn’t be asking him for a loan. He showed me his passbook. I understood why the Kerala government was in financial distress. Pattabhi mama was in his late 60’s and I could see another solid 40 years on him with improvements in technology and medicine. The Kerala government was bound to get bankrupt in the next 10 years only by paying Pattabhi Mama’s pension, not to mention the members of Pattabhi mama’s “Retried government employees who watch county cricket to pass time” club at Parmekkavu temple.</p>
<p>I was planning to suggest a portfolio of nifty index funds, gold and fixed deposits. But with his constant money supply outperforming benchmark indices, I fell on his feet doing a Shastanga Namaskaram.</p>
<hr>
<p>Note: There are three other stories in the Pattabhi Mama series.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/easwar_aiyer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.instagram.com/easwar_aiyer/</a></p>
<p>You can check the highlights to track them if you are interested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/06/03/crypto-mama/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Books I read in 2020</title>
		<link>/2021/05/28/books-i-read-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>/2021/05/28/books-i-read-in-2020/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sondha Kadhai Soga Kadhai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/05/28/books-i-read-in-2020/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the onset of the pandemic, work from home and living with my parents all combined I had a lot of time in my hands. Eventually I think we find ways to fill it up with something trivial. But during the transition I managed to read some books in the newly available free time and&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/05/28/books-i-read-in-2020/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the onset of the pandemic, work from home and living with my parents all combined I had a lot of time in my hands. Eventually I think we find ways to fill it up with something trivial. But during the transition I managed to read some books in the newly available free time and I hope some of these might pique your interest.</p>
<p>Tao Te Ching — Lao Tzu</p>
<p>One hundred years of solitude — Gabriel Garcia Marquez</p>
<p>The Brothers Karamazov — Fyodor Dostoyevsky</p>
<p>Much Obliged Jeeves — P G Wodehouse</p>
<p>Weekend Wodehouse — P G Wodehouse</p>
<p>Creativity — Osho</p>
<p>Six Easy Pieces — Richard Feynman</p>
<p>Stiff Upper Lip, Jeeves — P G Wodehouse</p>
<p>Uncle Fred in the Springtime — P G Wodehouse</p>
<p>Fear — Osho</p>
<p>Meetings with remarkable men — G I Gurdjieff</p>
<p>Gitanjali — Rabindranath Tagore</p>
<p>Who Am I? — Ramana Maharshi</p>
<p>Love, Freedom and Aloneness — Osho</p>
<p>Intuition — Osho</p>
<p>The Gospel of Ramakrishna</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/05/28/books-i-read-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Non-fiction</title>
		<link>/2021/05/26/non-fiction/</link>
					<comments>/2021/05/26/non-fiction/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 03:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sondha Kadhai Soga Kadhai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/05/26/non-fiction/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I realised that some of the best non-fiction books that I have read are approximately 150 pages or less. The communist manifesto, Why greatness cannot be planned, Six easy pieces by Feynman, Annihilation of caste by Ambedkar to name the ones that I can recall. This is not to imply that longer reads are of&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/05/26/non-fiction/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I realised that some of the best non-fiction books that I have read are approximately 150 pages or less.</p>
<p>The communist manifesto, Why greatness cannot be planned, Six easy pieces by Feynman, Annihilation of caste by Ambedkar to name the ones that I can recall.</p>
<p>This is not to imply that longer reads are of poor quality. But the percentage of good books is really high when the number of pages decreases. This could probably be due to the way the publishing industry works.</p>
<p>Really great ideas that could be communicated with a single blog post is puffed up due to the 60000 words requirement. This hit me hard when reading Krish Ashok‘s Masala Lab, personally I like all his work be it his tweets, blogs or songs, but the book did feel puffed up. Probably had he been given the liberty it could have been the cooking bible for “Tamil men/women doing tech jobs in chennai”.</p>
<p>I remember reading some essay by Wodehouse where he describes a crime thriller novelist’s approach towards writing. In those days they were paid per word and there was a scene where a killer kills the victim shooting him in the head. Even though a single round of firing would have done the job, the killer shot him six times, bang, bang, bang, bang, bang, bang. I hope you get the drift.</p>
<p>Really small books from publishers hit the shelves only if the content or the author breaks a certain quality barrier I suppose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/05/26/non-fiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Train to Madras</title>
		<link>/2021/05/16/train-to-madras/</link>
					<comments>/2021/05/16/train-to-madras/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 12:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sondha Kadhai Soga Kadhai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/05/16/train-to-madras/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before all this corona and lockdowns, I used to go to Thrissur about once a month during the weekends. I prefer the Alapuzha express whose departure and arrival follows the circadian rhythm of human beings unlike some other trains which seem to share a lineage with the Vampires, dropping us at 2 or 3 in&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/05/16/train-to-madras/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before all this corona and lockdowns, I used to go to Thrissur about once a month during the weekends. I prefer the Alapuzha express whose departure and arrival follows the circadian rhythm of human beings unlike some other trains which seem to share a lineage with the Vampires, dropping us at 2 or 3 in the morning. I would spend the weekend at Thrissur and come back to Madras on the same train.</p>
<p>I am used to waking up at 7 in the morning with no alarms. It’s the circadian rhythm you might assume. But my body probably trying to rebel with nature, chose it’s Modus Operandi to be the bowel movement cycle. Is it better than an actual alarm, I can’t say. But it’s certainly stricter with no “snooze” option available.</p>
<p>One weekend, the Alapuzha express reached Chennai at 6 in the morning and the cleaner woke me up when all the passengers had left. I remember reading something in ‘Thinking fast and slow’ where the author mentions that smiling is a causal effect of being happy. But you can trick your brain into being happy by just smiling. My bowels got tricked when I woke up at 6 too. “Living on the edge” is how I would describe my state of being at that moment.</p>
<p>I went to the toilet in the compartment. These were the days when most trains weren’t yet fitted with a bio toilet. I had a strong moral code to not do it on a standing train, added to that I also didn’t want some stranger in the platform to know that I had Biriyani for lunch the previous day.</p>
<p>I dropped my luggage in the waiting area and ran to the public toilet in the station. I thought I was the only one suffering from this issue, but it seemed to be a national issue. There were some 14 members standing in the queue already. I lost all hope. Any other queue, you could have asked the person in the front to show some sympathy because you had some urgent business. But everyone in this queue were already attending to their urgent business. I called upon all the gods to give me strength, for this was a battle akin to 300 Spartans trying to hold off a million Persians.</p>
<p>I noticed something special in the public toilet in the central station, there were two toilets and about 8 bathrooms. I want to know who is this OCD fellow who takes bath in a railway station. Or is it for people who soiled themselves due to the lack of availability of a toilet, only the station master can tell.</p>
<p>Probably due to some past lives’ karma points, I held the fort till my turn arrived. I was also silently praying for an Indian style toilet over a western one. As soon as I entered the toilet, whatever was trying to push its way out went right back in. I had wished for an Indian style toilet because the toilet seats are usually not so hygienic in a public place, but what I didn’t expect was the authorities removing the toilet seat altogether. I looked around, there was no place to hang my clothes either. I did what any resourceful person would do, I held the clothes in my underarm and put myself in a semi seated position trying to distance myself as much as I can from the commode. Thanks to my paying attention to the physics class in school, I was solving the equation for projectile motion standing in that semi seated position.</p>
<p>After the successful accomplishment of the task, I came out of the toilet and bid the other members of the queue a big goodbye, for we had been waiting there for so long that we had become thick friends.</p>
<p>If you read till here, you can also checkout this <a href="https://www.instagram.com/tv/B_uAOgHJgW8/" target="_blank">video</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/05/16/train-to-madras/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yogi And The Apprentice &#124; The Bodhi Tree</title>
		<link>/2021/04/27/yogi-and-the-apprentice-the-bodhi-tree/</link>
					<comments>/2021/04/27/yogi-and-the-apprentice-the-bodhi-tree/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Yogi and the Apprentice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/04/27/yogi-and-the-apprentice-the-bodhi-tree/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While walking along with the Yogi, Paddy noticed a banyan tree at the edge of the town. The banyan tree was surrounded by a circular pond of sand, beyond the circular pond were green lawns of grass. “Is that some Bodhi tree of some sorts?”, asked Paddy with a sense of boredom partially wanting to&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/04/27/yogi-and-the-apprentice-the-bodhi-tree/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While walking along with the Yogi, Paddy noticed a banyan tree at the edge of the town. The banyan tree was surrounded by a circular pond of sand, beyond the circular pond were green lawns of grass.</p>
<p>“Is that some Bodhi tree of some sorts?”, asked Paddy with a sense of boredom partially wanting to hear the story about it and partially not wanting to hear a similar story again.</p>
<p>“Theoretically yes Paddy, this tree has a major part to play with the origins of this town.” said the Yogi.</p>
<p>Before this town became a hub for the mystics and the occult it was like any other normal town. A monk once came and started meditating under this tree. Since his arrival, an old widow took care of his day to day necessities like food, water and clothing. She was the wife of the late headman of the village. During those times it was believed that the enlightenment of just one person would benefit all the people of the village. Hence the village or the well off people of the village would generally take care of the wanderers and meditators. She would take the essential items in cloth bags tied to the two ends of a stick and go to the monk every afternoon. The monk would be in deep meditation and the old lady wouldn’t disturb the monk and place the essentials and leave the place. This happened for 25 years, the old lady was getting older and she could no longer go to the banyan tree herself to serve the monk.</p>
<p>There was a tea stall opposite the old lady’s house and she asked the tea master to take the food and other essentials to the monk. She also asked the tea master to enquire the monk on whether he has attained enlightenment.</p>
<p>“Is this the same tea master we met in Varanasi?” asked Paddy.</p>
<p>“This is an old story paddy, he is also from the order of Tea Masters and now stop interrupting” said the Yogi.</p>
<p>The tea master went to the banyan tree and asked the monk exactly what was requested by the old lady.</p>
<p>“The old lady wants to know, in this 25 years of meditation have you attained enlightenment?” asked the Tea Master.</p>
<p>The monk opened his eyes from meditation.</p>
<p>“I attained enlightenment within the first 5 years of meditating under this tree, for the last 20 years I am experiencing bliss” said the monk.</p>
<p>The tea master smiled and went back to the old lady to tell her the news.</p>
<p>“Oh, old lady, the monk has attained enlightenment, but he hasn’t gone beyond it.” said the Tea Master.</p>
<p>It was probably because of the presence of the Tea Master, the old lady didn’t need further explanation. She knew what lay beyond without knowing it.</p>
<p>“See I don’t understand why you always talk in paradoxes, it makes no sense” said Paddy.</p>
<p>“Not all paradoxes are truths paddy, but all truths are paradoxes. Additionally it also sounds cool Paddy.” said the Yogi.</p>
<p>Bees find nectar bearing flowers no matter where it’s hidden. The flowers need no social media campaign or tele marketing events.</p>
<p>In time, mystics and occults started to find the old lady in this village and it slowly turned into what it is today.</p>
<p>“So what happened to that monk?” asked Paddy.</p>
<p>“He is like any other person Paddy, trying to latch on to previous experiences, but can there be an experience without an experiencer?” asked the Yogi.</p>
<p>“See, I have heard enough of this ego dropping bullshit, is there something beyond enlightenment? Isn’t enlightenment supposed to be the end goal?” asked Paddy.</p>
<p>“Beyond enlightenment there is nothingness Paddy, like the Tea master you could always skip the enlightenment part and jump to nothingness. The pursuit of enlightenment is overrated Paddy. You don’t need to do anything to jump into nothingness, it’s ever present and all around us. It’s a great mystery how people keep missing what is around them and go for sudarshana kriya workshops. Why put in so much effort for something that requires no effort?” said the Yogi.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/04/27/yogi-and-the-apprentice-the-bodhi-tree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">215</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>God Save Tamil Nadu</title>
		<link>/2021/04/06/god-save-tamil-nadu/</link>
					<comments>/2021/04/06/god-save-tamil-nadu/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 05:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/04/06/god-save-tamil-nadu/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No matter who wins the 2021 Tamil Nadu election, it’s going to change the political landscape of Tamil Nadu. If the DMK wins, the ADMK will no longer be the same party that we see now. If the ADMK wins the election, the Karunanidhi family won’t be as powerful as they are within the DMK.&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2021/04/06/god-save-tamil-nadu/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No matter who wins the 2021 Tamil Nadu election, it’s going to change the political landscape of Tamil Nadu. If the DMK wins, the ADMK will no longer be the same party that we see now. If the ADMK wins the election, the Karunanidhi family won’t be as powerful as they are within the DMK. Writing this now as on April 6th 2021, it seems that nothing could go wrong with the DMK and everything should fall in place for Stalin to become the next CM.</p>
<p>Ideologically, the then DMK of 1960’s can be seen as today’s Naam Tamilar Katchi, with more success. The ideology could lead to ardent fan following as well as staunch hatred. The Anti DMK votes are primarily cast towards the ADMK which itself inherited the Anti DMK votes from the Congress during the time of MGR, because of the perceived winnability.</p>
<p>Where would the Anti DMK votes go after this election is the question. With the current parties and characters in play, no face is winnable enough to garner all the anti DMK votes.</p>
<p>There are two scenarios that could unfold, a people’s movement like the anti corruption movement or the ram janmabhoomi movement could give rise to a new party or leadership.</p>
<p>Two, an established personality with the necessary infrastructure in place like MGR, Rajini might draw the anti DMK votes as well. With our current scope of vision, Vijay seems to be that candidate. The Anti DMK votes, the neutral votes looking for change from the DMK/ADMK and strategic alliances could very well whip up a new front.</p>
<p>Personally I like none of the above scenarios and looking at them I have only one thing to wish for, God save Tamil Nadu.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/04/06/god-save-tamil-nadu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trigger Words</title>
		<link>/2020/10/27/trigger-words/</link>
					<comments>/2020/10/27/trigger-words/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 04:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sondha Kadhai Soga Kadhai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2020/10/27/trigger-words/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some words are used and abused so much that you hate the word even if it is used in the right context. One such word that has sprung up since the advent of instagram is ‘crazy’. I get that you and your friend from college share some fond memories and looking back at it you&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2020/10/27/trigger-words/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some words are used and abused so much that you hate the word even if it is used in the right context.</p>
<p>One such word that has sprung up since the advent of instagram is ‘crazy’.</p>
<p>I get that you and your friend from college share some fond memories and looking back at it you feel good about it. But this in no way justifies your caption of “For all the crazy things that we did in college”. If you had gone to the class just wearing your underpants and came out unscathed without a suspension, now that would amount to ‘crazy’. Going to McDonalds in the weekend and eating french fries is not #crazy.</p>
<p>As if attributing moments as crazy is not enough, people attribute other people and in extension themselves as ‘crazy’ on their instagram posts.</p>
<p>“The only person in the world who is as crazy as me”</p>
<p>Let me tell you something, you are not as crazy and fun as you think, but pretty boring and unoriginal even in your captions. I think there is an innate need for everyone to portray themselves as a rebel, while the only rebellion that they had ever done against the society is getting a tattoo, colouring the hair or getting a hair cut of their preference.</p>
<p>Another usage that has propped up in recent times is the use of Bell Peppers. Dei, Capsicum kundi, why this sudden transformation after watching master chef on youtube? What happened to the Kodamolaga days while watching Sunday Samayal with Paravai Muniyamma?</p>
<p>The underlying theme of replacement of known words in society I think is to disassociate oneself from the crowd. Similar to “I read Dostoevsky after dinner, what da you silly fellow still reading Chetan Bhagat?”</p>
<p>The need to differentiate oneself from the mob has always existed in some form. But the method of differentiation seems to be about getting into another mob. A transition from the old mob to the new mob, at the end of it confirmed to the society.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/10/27/trigger-words/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">217</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toilet Stories</title>
		<link>/2020/10/21/toilet-stories/</link>
					<comments>/2020/10/21/toilet-stories/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 02:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2020/10/21/toilet-stories/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like we are at a point where climate change is irreversible. Recently also I read a blog on how to brush teeth in one cup of water. Every drop of water you save, you are going to cling on to this city, posting blogs the next year also about how to wash hands&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2020/10/21/toilet-stories/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like we are at a point where climate change is irreversible. Recently also I read a blog on how to brush teeth in one cup of water. Every drop of water you save, you are going to cling on to this city, posting blogs the next year also about how to wash hands with 2 ml of water. So now, when I brush my teeth, I turn the shower on, just to speed up the process.</p>
<p>It’s not like I never tried to save the environment.</p>
<p>After a heavy lunch on a certain Wednesday in office, I immediately went to the toilet. I performed the task that is meant to be performed in the toilet. After the completion of the task, I had two choices. I could either use the jet spray and waste water, or do the cleaning American style and save the environment. I chose the environment. But the thing is, I had never done this before.</p>
<p>I was brought up in a lower middle class family in Chennai. We lived in a 1BHK house with 1 Indian style toilet. When I was a kid, if I saw a western toilet, I would promptly climb over it and do my business. In my mind, if you had a western toilet in your house you must be filthy rich. Only later did I realise that I was filthy poor.</p>
<p>But my dad had an explanation for everything. He was a well educated poor person.</p>
<p>I asked him, “Appa, appa, why don’t we have western toilet in our house?”.</p>
<p>He said, “Easwar, Indian style toilets are actually better by design, the way you sit in an Indian toilet is actually a yogasana, which is pretty beneficial for your bowels”.</p>
<p>“Oho, benefit to the bowel and all is good to hear, but I heard Kokila paati did a somersault while trying to sit in the toilet and is in the ICU?”</p>
<p>“That is Darwin’s theory holding it’s own son, you can’t blame the Indian toilet for it” he said.</p>
<p>Coming back to the story, I used the tissue to do the ritual. I did it once, I did it twice, I did it over countless times, but there was never a sense of fulfillment.</p>
<p>Neither did I have the confidence to wear my white Jockey underpants back on nor did I have any tissues left. This was when I realised the level of confidence that our ancestors had, komanam and langod were always white.</p>
<p>Which American model have you seen wearing white jockey underpants?</p>
<p>Then I googled the amount of water used to make one roll of tissue. 12 to 37 gallons of water was google’s answer. That settled it for me.</p>
<p>I used the jet spray and wore my underpants with full confidence, and put the tissues into the dustbin along with my idea of saving the environment.</p>
<h4>Environmentalists and Public Toilets</h4>
<p>When people blog about being cautious about how we flush to avoid wastage of water, some people directly take it to their heart and don’t flush altogether.</p>
<p>I don’t understand what goes on in their mind. “I have done my business here, the next person is also going to do the same thing, he can flush it all together. Saves a lot of water, you see.”</p>
<p>Or do they think it’s some form of relay, where you pass the baton to the next person coming? “I’ll do the shitting, here take the baton, now you go do the flushing.”</p>
<p>We could actually give the benefit of doubt to the person. Maybe the flush wasn’t effective in cleaning. But we do have a jet spray. And the jet spray has so much pressure that it gives a push back like an AK-47. Some of the jet sprays could be used in factories for metal cutting.</p>
<p>First I thought, people didn’t know how to use the jet spray. But evidence proved that they had used it everywhere else except the closet. Usually one has to swim through the puddle of water to get to the closet.</p>
<p>The line of thinking got me to the possible solutions for this.</p>
<ol>
<li>Mandate that every lunch should consist only of curd rice.This will remove the adhevise properties of the remnants of the biological combustion engine.</li>
<li>Aadhar card swiping to get into the public toilets and image processing tech for pre and post usage, google pay integration for fines can be in the roadmap.</li>
</ol>
<p>Or we could just be a little sensible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/10/21/toilet-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">218</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures of Kittumani</title>
		<link>/2020/10/20/adventures-of-kittumani/</link>
					<comments>/2020/10/20/adventures-of-kittumani/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 08:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2020/10/20/adventures-of-kittumani/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cricket stadium was packed to the brim. The bowler was already sweating out of fear, he knew who the batsman was, he started his run up as soon as the umpire signalled him to bowl, he stood a hint of a chance only if he bowled the perfect yorker, ball after ball for the&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2020/10/20/adventures-of-kittumani/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The cricket stadium was packed to the brim. The bowler was already sweating out of fear, he knew who the batsman was, he started his run up as soon as the umpire signalled him to bowl, he stood a hint of a chance only if he bowled the perfect yorker, ball after ball for the next six balls. As soon as he released the ball he knew that it was going to be the perfect yorker, but the batsman facing the ball was Kittumani, he gradually walked down the ground, converted it into a full toss and hit it over the long off fielder for a six. The next ball was a wide full toss, Kittumani cleared that ball out of the ground as well for a six. He hit three more consecutive sixes around the ground and the last ball he decided to take just a single to face as many balls as he could in an innings. The commentators called him a prodigy, Sachin Tendulkar called him the player of the century and Shoaib Akthar called him the Rajdhani express for his bowling capabilities.</p>
<p>“Dei Kittumani, you want your gaji or not?” asked Vignesh.</p>
<p>“Huh?..ahn.. Yeah yeah” said Kittumani coming out of his template fantasy.</p>
<p>Kittumani was in his 5th standard and Vicky in his 7th. Vicky was living in the ground floor of the same apartment that Kittumani was living in. Since he was the oldest of the lot, Vicky did all the organizing that it took for a game of cricket.</p>
<p>The previous batsman was declared out based on the “one pitch one hand” rule. The batsman Hari had then accused the fielder of not just using his hand, but his thighs, abdomen and chest to hold on to the ball which went against the very fabric of the “one pitch one hand” rule. The argument lasted for about 5 minutes around when the fielder Abu who was the richest kid in the club reminded the arguing crowd about the ownership of the Milo bat, the owner being the fielder Abu himself. The crowd declared that the argument had enough strength in itself to declare the judgement in favor of the fielder. The umpire Sriram who was from the batting team declared that the batsman is indeed out and that the umpire’s decision is the final decision. The umpire Sriram who was himself from the batting team also secretly wanted Hari to get out since he was the best player in the club and if he kept on playing there was no way that he would get his gaji before the overs ran out.</p>
<p>Kittumani took hold of the Milo bat from Hari and walked on to the crease. The crease being the narrow tar road in front of his house, both ends of the street were covered with buildings with just one empty plot. The stumps were made of a cuboidal tar tin over which a couple of bricks were placed to account for the appropriate height. The stumps over the other end was just one big stone about a few inches tall. Current shock, the practice of catching the ball with one’s hand and placing just the legs on the stumps was banned in the club and even the suggestion of current shock was frowned upon.</p>
<p>Kittumani adjusted his jatti as he had seen numerous times on television. He went down the crease and tapped on the tar road a few times with his milo bat and came back satisfied. Nobody in the club really knew why it was done on television, but Hari had once not done this double tap on the road and had gotten out on the first ball. Hari was the only guy going for cricket coaching in the club and was indisputably the best player. From then on it was a ritual that all the members of the club followed without any questions asked.</p>
<p>Kittumani was in his batting stance and the bowler from the other end took the longest run up, the highest jump and the loudest grunt while delivering the ball. But despite all that Manga Mohan’s elbows would always end up bending, just about 180 degrees. The club since the time of its inception had even seen their fair share of dogs with straight tails, but it was impossible to make Manga Mohan’s arms straight while bowling. The club decided to provide an exception for Manga alone since even with all the running, jumping, grunting and manga(ing), the ball travelled at not more than 10 Km/h.</p>
<p>The ball left Manga’s hands, Kittumani could see the ball clearly in 1080p as it was coming in slow motion. He swung his bat wildly, the bat missed the ball, the ball missed the stumps, and the keeper missed to hold the ball as well. And this repeated for about 3 more balls after which the captain Vicky was begging Manga to stand and bowl straight onto the stumps. But manga was a proud bowler idolising Shoib Akthar, he always wished to run from the end of the street.</p>
<p>With the final ball, Kittumani was determined to make this one count, he swung the bat with such ferociousness that the bat slipped out of his hand and went straight into the empty plot after which the owner of the bat Abu decided to end the game citing that the game was getting too dangerous for the Milo bat.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/10/20/adventures-of-kittumani/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trains and Alms</title>
		<link>/2020/10/11/trains-and-alms/</link>
					<comments>/2020/10/11/trains-and-alms/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[easwaraiyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 13:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2020/10/11/trains-and-alms/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[People asking for alms is pretty common in the local trains. Remember the first time that someone ever asked you for alms, how we wondered how the world is so unfair, why the world couldn’t be a much nicer place, how fortunate we are to lead the lives that we already do. At last we&#8230;<span class="excerpt-more-link"><a class="more-link" href="/2020/10/11/trains-and-alms/">More <svg class="svg-icon" width="24" height="24" aria-hidden="true" role="img" focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M6.96954 10.2804L11.9999 15.3107L17.0302 10.2804L15.9695 9.21973L11.9999 13.1894L8.0302 9.21973L6.96954 10.2804Z" fill="currentColor"/></svg></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People asking for alms is pretty common in the local trains. Remember the first time that someone ever asked you for alms, how we wondered how the world is so unfair, why the world couldn’t be a much nicer place, how fortunate we are to lead the lives that we already do. At last we end up giving the person 1 Rs and derive the same satisfaction that Karna did while donating his Kavacha kuntala to Indra.</p>
<p>But the high doesn’t last for long, since in a single train journey you are going to be requested for alms by at least 8 different people. You become the pragmatist that Krishna was and realise that the world is intrinsically unfair.</p>
<p>Regular passengers in the local trains are the Picassos of avoiding a donation. The layman would try avoiding eye contact by looking at the mobile screen, out of the window or starting a conversation with a total stranger at the side. The regular passengers avoid eye contact by sleeping even when on a footboard.</p>
<p>I have tried to follow this practice of actually looking the person in the eye and telling them that I don’t have any change. Avoiding eye contact I feel is pretty disrespectful. It’s atleast bettter to look them in the eye and lie to them respectfully. But this act also places me in a bind at times when the person selling cut mangoes, the person asking for alms and I coincide like the sun, moon and the earth during a solar eclipse.</p>
<p>I might be ruthless enough to lie that “I don’t have any change” to a beggar, but not so ruthless as to buy the cut mangoes infront of the beggar and say “I don’t have any change NOW”.</p>
<p>I don’t give alms to anyone except for the transgender community, for them I have a soft corner in my heart.</p>
<p>Regular passengers who are Picassos of avoiding a donation instantly turn into painter Purushtoman when the transgenders arrive asking for alms. You look out the window, they turn your head their way. You sleep act, they pat strong on the face. You start a conversation with a stranger, they ll become the moderator of the debate.</p>
<p>I had once told them that I don’t have any change, for which the prompt reply was, “We accept 100’s too”. Now there was no way for me to go back on my word even though all that I had in my wallet was 1’s 2’s and 5’s. From then on, even before the transgenders come into the bogey, I keep 10 rs ready in my right jeans pocket.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/10/11/trains-and-alms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">220</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
